<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Recent Software Dev Courses</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com</link><description>Latest software development courses from O'Reilly</description><item><title>Must-Have Tools for IT Support: Remote Access, AI, and Troubleshooting</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.comhttps://learning.oreilly.com/api/v1/book/9780135584439/chapter/MHTIS1_01_01_06.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;1.6 PC Anywhere&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:42:09 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>AI Insights (Video Collection)</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.comhttps://learning.oreilly.com/api/v1/book/9780135570210/chapter/AIMRAGCM1_01_02_01.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;RAG Breakthroughs&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:42:09 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CompTIA PenTest+ (PT0-003)</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.comhttps://learning.oreilly.com/api/v1/book/9781835887424/chapter/video2_10.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In the video, we will explore essential strategies for addressing security vulnerabilities. As cybersecurity professionals, our role extends beyond identifying weaknesses; we must also provide practical, actionable solutions. This video will guide you through various remediation approaches, categorized into technical, administrative, operational, and physical controls. Understanding these categories and the specific actions within each will enable you to recommend comprehensive solutions that strengthen an organization's security posture, a skill directly applicable to your future careers as penetration testers and cybersecurity specialists.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:42:09 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Security Superstream: Secure Code in the Age of AI</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.comhttps://learning.oreilly.com/api/v1/book/0642572020325/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;AI tools are transforming the ways that we write and deploy code, making development faster and more efficient, but they also introduce new risks and vulnerabilities. To protect organizations, security must remain a paramount concern across the entire AI ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Join top security professionals, software engineers, developers, data scientists, and AI specialists as they share practical insights, real-world experiences, and emerging trends to address the full spectrum of AI security. Whether you’re focused on secure coding practices, building and deploying secure models, or protecting against AI-specific threats, this event offers valuable perspectives on ensuring that your systems remain secure in an increasingly AI-driven world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;What you’ll learn and how you can apply it&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Understand and apply AI security frameworks such as MAESTRO and the Databricks AI Security Framework&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Test the security of AI systems with AI red team best practices&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Defend AI systems from the biggest threats with MITRE ATLAS&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Explore AI safety risks and how to mitigate them&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Recommended follow-up&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Read &lt;a href="https://learning.oreilly.com/library/view/not-with-a/9781119883982/"&gt;Not with a Bug, But with a Sticker&lt;/a&gt; (book)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Read &lt;a href="https://learning.oreilly.com/library/view/the-developers-playbook/9781098162191/"&gt;The Developer’s Playbook for Large Language Model Security&lt;/a&gt; (book)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please note that slides or supplemental materials are not available for download from this recording. Resources are only provided at the time of the live event.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:42:09 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Container Security, 2nd Edition</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.comhttps://learning.oreilly.com/api/v1/book/9798341627697/chapter/ch08.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;No description available.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:42:09 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sustainable AI</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.comhttps://learning.oreilly.com/api/v1/book/9781098155506/chapter/ch09.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;No description available.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:42:09 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Effective Platform Engineering</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.comhttps://learning.oreilly.com/api/v1/book/9781633436497/chapter/Text/chapter-2.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;No description available.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:42:09 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Building Agentic AI: Workflows, Fine-Tuning, Optimization, and Deployment</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.comhttps://learning.oreilly.com/api/v1/book/9780135489710/chapter/ch07.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;No description available.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:42:09 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Building Enterprise-Ready Azure Infrastructure: Learn Security, Scalability, and Reliability with IaC &amp; DevOps</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.comhttps://learning.oreilly.com/api/v1/book/9798868818110/chapter/html/660411_1_En_3_Chapter.xhtml</link><description>&lt;p&gt;No description available.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:42:09 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Doing Enterprise-Architecture: A Maturity-Model Guide to Architecture Development</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.comhttps://learning.oreilly.com/api/v1/book/9798868817571/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; line-height: normal; mso-pagination: widow-orphan; mso-hyphenate: auto; text-autospace: ideograph-numeric ideograph-other; mso-vertical-align-alt: auto;"&gt;Enterprise architecture is a set of business practices that connect an organization’s strategy with its management of change. It is concerned with the structure and story of the enterprise, and ensuring that everything across the whole enterprise will work together in the most effective way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; line-height: normal; mso-pagination: widow-orphan; mso-hyphenate: auto; text-autospace: ideograph-numeric ideograph-other; mso-vertical-align-alt: auto;"&gt;Yet when doing enterprise architecture, what should we do, in what sequence, and for what business purpose? What skills and leadership do we need? What results should we expect? And how can we prove the business value of what we do? This book sets out to answer those questions and show how, with the right architecture support, every change in the organization can be a change for the better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; line-height: normal; mso-pagination: widow-orphan; mso-hyphenate: auto; text-autospace: ideograph-numeric ideograph-other; mso-vertical-align-alt: auto;"&gt;The book explains that to achieve this, we will need a literal ‘architecture of the enterprise’ that can start anywhere and can address every aspect of the enterprise, including people, machines, IT and more. We will need architecture development methods that can work consistently and in the same way everywhere, for every type of content or context, at every scope and scale, with every timescale, and throughout every stage of the change process. We will need those methods to support not just planned change, but provide continuity over longer periods, These methods must also respond fast to unexpected opportunities, risks and large-scale challenges arising within the organization and its market, and from the real-world beyond the enterprise itself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; line-height: normal; mso-pagination: widow-orphan; mso-hyphenate: auto; text-autospace: ideograph-numeric ideograph-other; mso-vertical-align-alt: auto;"&gt;The book describes how to satisfy all of those needs, using a formal dependency-driven maturity-model to guide systematic step-by-step development of the organization’s capabilities for enterprise architecture. The sequence of steps ensures that, at each stage of development, the architecture can be relied upon to achieve desired, effective business outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; line-height: normal; mso-pagination: widow-orphan; mso-hyphenate: auto; text-autospace: ideograph-numeric ideograph-other; mso-vertical-align-alt: auto;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You Will&lt;/strong&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;"&gt;Learn how to extend your architecture beyond IT to the whole enterprise.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;"&gt;Learn how to use a service-based approach to enhance consistency across the whole architecture.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="MsoNormal" style="line-height: normal;"&gt;Learn how to enhance efficiency, effectiveness, responsiveness and resilience throughout the enterprise.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; line-height: normal; mso-pagination: widow-orphan; mso-hyphenate: auto; text-autospace: ideograph-numeric ideograph-other; mso-vertical-align-alt: auto;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; line-height: normal; mso-pagination: widow-orphan; mso-hyphenate: auto; text-autospace: ideograph-numeric ideograph-other; mso-vertical-align-alt: auto;"&gt;This book is for : Enterprise Architects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; line-height: normal; mso-pagination: widow-orphan; mso-hyphenate: auto; text-autospace: ideograph-numeric ideograph-other; mso-vertical-align-alt: auto;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:42:09 -0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>