<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>O'Reilly Developer Courses</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/</link><description>Latest developer courses from O'Reilly</description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 16:17:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>AI Engineering 👨‍🏫 Chip Huyen 📅 2024-12-04</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/library/view/ai-engineering/9781098166298/</link><description>&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Recent breakthroughs in AI have not only increased demand for AI products, they&amp;#x27;ve also lowered the barriers to entry for those who want to build AI products. The model-as-a-service approach has transformed AI from an esoteric discipline into a powerful development tool that anyone can use. Everyone, including those with minimal or no prior AI experience, can now leverage AI models to build applications. In this book, author Chip Huyen discusses AI engineering: the process of building applications with readily available foundation models.  
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
The book starts with an overview of AI engineering, explaining how it differs from traditional ML engineering and discussing the new AI stack. The more AI is used, the more opportunities there are for catastrophic failures, and therefore, the more important evaluation becomes. This book discusses different approaches to evaluating open-ended models, including the rapidly growing AI-as-a-judge approach.
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
AI application developers will discover how to navigate the AI landscape, including models, datasets, evaluation benchmarks, and the seemingly infinite number of use cases and application patterns. You&amp;#x27;ll learn a framework for developing an AI application, starting with simple techniques and progressing toward more sophisticated methods, and discover how to efficiently deploy these applications.
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Understand what AI engineering is and how it differs from traditional machine learning engineering 
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Learn the process for developing an AI application, the challenges at each step, and approaches to address them 
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Explore various model adaptation techniques, including prompt engineering, RAG, fine-tuning, agents, and dataset engineering, and understand how and why they work
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Examine the bottlenecks for latency and cost when serving foundation models and learn how to overcome them
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Choose the right model, dataset, evaluation benchmarks, and metrics for your needs
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Chip Huyen works to accelerate data analytics on GPUs at Voltron Data. Previously, she was with Snorkel AI and NVIDIA, founded an AI infrastructure startup, and taught Machine Learning Systems Design at Stanford. She&amp;#x27;s the author of the book Designing Machine Learning Systems, an Amazon bestseller in AI.
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;AI Engineering&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; builds upon and is complementary to &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Designing Machine Learning Systems (O&amp;#x27;Reilly)&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;</description><enclosure url="https://learning.oreilly.com/library/cover/9781098166298/" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Hands-On Large Language Models 👨‍🏫 Jay Alammar, Maarten Grootendorst 📅 2024-09-11</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/library/view/hands-on-large-language/9781098150952/</link><description>&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;AI has acquired startling new language capabilities in just the past few years. Driven by rapid advances in deep learning, language AI systems are able to write and understand text better than ever before. This trend is enabling new features, products, and entire industries. Through this book&amp;#x27;s visually educational nature, readers will learn practical tools and concepts they need to use these capabilities today.
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You&amp;#x27;ll understand how to use pretrained large language models for use cases like copywriting and summarization; create semantic search systems that go beyond keyword matching; and use existing libraries and pretrained models for text classification, search, and clusterings. 
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This book also helps you:
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Understand the architecture of Transformer language models that excel at text generation and representation&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Build advanced LLM pipelines to cluster text documents and explore the topics they cover&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Build semantic search engines that go beyond keyword search, using methods like dense retrieval and rerankers&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Explore how generative models can be used, from prompt engineering all the way to retrieval-augmented generation&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Gain a deeper understanding of how to train LLMs and optimize them for specific applications using generative model fine-tuning, contrastive fine-tuning, and in-context learning&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;</description><enclosure url="https://learning.oreilly.com/library/cover/9781098150952/" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Designing Data-Intensive Applications, 2nd Edition 👨‍🏫 Martin Kleppmann, Chris Riccomini 📅 2026-02-25</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/library/view/designing-data-intensive-applications/9781098119058/</link><description>&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;Data is at the center of many challenges in system design today. Difficult issues such as scalability, consistency, reliability, efficiency, and maintainability need to be resolved. In addition, there&amp;#x27;s an overwhelming variety of tools and analytical systems, including relational databases, NoSQL datastores, plus data warehouses and data lakes. What are the right choices for your application? How do you make sense of all these buzzwords?
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
In this second edition, authors Martin Kleppmann and Chris Riccomini build on the foundation laid in the acclaimed first edition, integrating new technologies and emerging trends. You&amp;#x27;ll be guided through the maze of decisions and trade-offs involved in building a modern data system, from choosing the right tools like Spark and Flink to understanding the intricacies of data laws like the GDPR.
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Peer under the hood of the systems you already use, and learn to use them more effectively
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Make informed decisions by identifying the strengths and weaknesses of different tools
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Navigate the trade-offs around consistency, scalability, fault tolerance, and complexity
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Understand the distributed systems research upon which modern databases are built
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Peek behind the scenes of major online services, and learn from their architectures
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;</description><enclosure url="https://learning.oreilly.com/library/cover/9781098119058/" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Hands-On Machine Learning with Scikit-Learn, Keras, and TensorFlow, 3rd Edition 👨‍🏫 Aurélien Géron 📅 2022-10-04</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/library/view/hands-on-machine-learning/9781098125967/</link><description>&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Through a recent series of breakthroughs, deep learning has boosted the entire field of machine learning. Now, even programmers who know close to nothing about this technology can use simple, efficient tools to implement programs capable of learning from data. This bestselling book uses concrete examples, minimal theory, and production-ready Python frameworks (Scikit-Learn, Keras, and TensorFlow) to help you gain an intuitive understanding of the concepts and tools for building intelligent systems. 
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
With this updated third edition, author Aurélien Géron explores a range of techniques, starting with simple linear regression and progressing to deep neural networks. Numerous code examples and exercises throughout the book help you apply what you&amp;#x27;ve learned. Programming experience is all you need to get started. 
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Use Scikit-learn to track an example ML project end to end 
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Explore several models, including support vector machines, decision trees, random forests, and ensemble methods 
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Exploit unsupervised learning techniques such as dimensionality reduction, clustering, and anomaly detection 
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Dive into neural net architectures, including convolutional nets, recurrent nets, generative adversarial networks, autoencoders, diffusion models, and transformers 
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Use TensorFlow and Keras to build and train neural nets for computer vision, natural language processing, generative models, and deep reinforcement learning 
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;</description><enclosure url="https://learning.oreilly.com/library/cover/9781098125967/" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Build a Large Language Model (From Scratch) 👨‍🏫 Sebastian Raschka 📅 2024-09-11</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/library/view/build-a-large/9781633437166/</link><description>&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Learn how to create, train, and tweak large language models (LLMs) by building one from the ground up!&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;

In &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;Build a Large Language Model (from Scratch)&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; bestselling author Sebastian Raschka guides you step by step through creating your own LLM. Each stage is explained with clear text, diagrams, and examples. You’ll go from the initial design and creation, to pretraining on a general corpus, and on to fine-tuning for specific tasks.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;Build a Large Language Model (from Scratch)&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; teaches you how to:&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Plan and code all the parts of an LLM&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Prepare a dataset suitable for LLM training&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Fine-tune LLMs for text classification and with your own data&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Use human feedback to ensure your LLM follows instructions&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Load pretrained weights into an LLM&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;Build a Large Language Model (from Scratch)&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; takes you inside the AI black box to tinker with the internal systems that power generative AI. As you work through each key stage of LLM creation, you’ll develop an in-depth understanding of how LLMs work, their limitations, and their customization methods. Your LLM can be developed on an ordinary laptop, and used as your own personal assistant.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;About the Technology&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Physicist Richard P. Feynman reportedly said, “I don’t understand anything I can’t build.” Based on this same powerful principle, bestselling author Sebastian Raschka guides you step by step as you build a GPT-style LLM that you can run on your laptop. This is an engaging book that covers each stage of the process, from planning and coding to training and fine-tuning.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;About the Book&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;Build a Large Language Model (From Scratch)&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; is a practical and eminently-satisfying hands-on journey into the foundations of generative AI. Without relying on any existing LLM libraries, you’ll code a base model, evolve it into a text classifier, and ultimately create a chatbot that can follow your conversational instructions. And you’ll really understand it because you built it yourself!&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;

For deeper understanding and better learning we provide a built-in testing system into liveBook, the online version of this book. Separately, you can download a free PDF Test Yourself guide on this book from &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://www.manning.com/books/test-yourself-on-build-a-large-language-model-from-scratch&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot;&amp;gt;here.&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;What&amp;#x27;s Inside&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Plan and code an LLM comparable to GPT-2&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Load pretrained weights&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Construct a complete training pipeline&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Fine-tune your LLM for text classification&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Develop LLMs that follow human instructions&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;About the Reader&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;Readers need intermediate Python skills and some knowledge of machine learning. The LLM you create will run on any modern laptop and can optionally utilize GPUs.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;About the Author&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Sebastian Raschka&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;, PhD, is an LLM Research Engineer with over a decade of experience in artificial intelligence. His work spans industry  and academia, including implementing LLM solutions as a senior engineer at Lightning AI and teaching as a statistics professor at the University of Wisconsin–Madison.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;

Sebastian collaborates with Fortune 500 companies on AI solutions and serves on the Open Source Board at University of Wisconsin–Madison. He specializes in LLMs and the development of high-performance AI systems, with a deep focus on practical, code-driven implementations. He is the author of the bestselling books &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;Machine Learning with PyTorch and Scikit-Learn&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;, and &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;Machine Learning Q and AI&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;.

&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;

The technical editor on this book was &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;David Caswell&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Quotes&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;Truly inspirational! It motivates you to put your new skills into action.&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;- Benjamin Muskalla, Senior Engineer, GitHub&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;The most understandable and comprehensive explanation of language models yet! Its unique and practical teaching style achieves a level of understanding you can’t get any other way.&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;- Cameron Wolfe, Senior Scientist, Netflix&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;Sebastian combines deep knowledge with practical engineering skills and a knack for making complex ideas simple. This is the guide you need!&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;- Chip Huyen, author of Designing Machine Learning Systems and AI Engineering&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;Definitive, up-to-date coverage. Highly recommended!&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;- Dr. Vahid Mirjalili, Senior Data Scientist, FM Global&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;</description><enclosure url="https://learning.oreilly.com/library/cover/9781633437166/" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Learning Python, 6th Edition 👨‍🏫 Mark Lutz 📅 2025-02-26</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/library/view/learning-python-6th/9781098171292/</link><description>&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Get a comprehensive, in-depth introduction to the core Python language with this hands-on book. Based on author Mark Lutz&amp;#x27;s popular training course, this updated sixth edition will help you quickly write efficient, high-quality code with Python. It&amp;#x27;s an ideal way to begin, whether you&amp;#x27;re new to programming or a professional developer versed in other languages.
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
Complete with quizzes, exercises, and helpful illustrations, this easy-to-follow self-paced tutorial gets you started with Python 3.12 and all other releases in use today. With a pragmatic focus on what you need to know, it also introduces some advanced language features that have become increasingly common in Python code.
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
This book helps you:
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Explore Python&amp;#x27;s built-in object types such as strings, lists, dictionaries, and files
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Create and process objects with Python statements, and learn Python&amp;#x27;s syntax model
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Use functions and functional programming to avoid redundancy and maximize reuse
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Organize code into larger components with modules and packages
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Code robust programs with Python&amp;#x27;s exception handling and development tools
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Apply object-oriented programming and classes to make code customizable
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Survey advanced Python tools including decorators, descriptors, and metaclasses
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Write idiomatic Python code that runs portably across a wide variety of platforms
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;</description><enclosure url="https://learning.oreilly.com/library/cover/9781098171292/" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>ISC2 CISSP Certified Information Systems Security Professional Official Study Guide, 10th Edition 👨‍🏫 Mike Chapple, James Michael Stewart, Darril Gibson 📅 2024-06-12</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/library/view/isc2-cissp-certified/9781394254699/</link><description>&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;CISSP Study Guide - fully updated for the 2024 CISSP Body of Knowledge&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;ISC2 Certified Information Systems Security Professional (CISSP) Official Study Guide, 10th Edition&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; has been completely updated based on the latest 2024 CISSP Detailed Content Outline. This bestselling Sybex Study Guide covers 100% of the CISSP objectives. You&amp;#x27;ll prepare smarter and faster with Sybex thanks to expert content, knowledge from our real-world experience, access to the Sybex online interactive learning environment, and much more. Reinforce what you&amp;#x27;ve learned with key topic Study Essentials and chapter review questions.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The book’s co-authors bring decades of experience as cybersecurity practitioners and educators, integrating real-world expertise with the practical knowledge you&amp;#x27;ll need to successfully prove your CISSP mastery. Combined, they&amp;#x27;ve taught cybersecurity concepts to millions of students through their books, video courses, and live training programs.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Along with the book, you also get access to Sybex&amp;#x27;s superior online interactive learning environment that includes:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Over 900 practice test questions with complete answer explanations. This includes all of the questions from the book plus four additional online-only practice exams, each with 125 unique questions. You can use the online-only practice exams as full exam simulations. Our questions will help you identify where you need to study more.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;More than 1000 Electronic Flashcards to reinforce your learning and give you last-minute test prep &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;A searchable glossary in PDF to give you instant access to the key terms you need to know &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Audio Review.&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Author Mike Chapple reads the Study Essentials for each chapter providing you with more than 2 hours of up-to-date audio review for yet another way to reinforce your knowledge as you prepare.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Coverage of all of the CISSP topics in the book means you&amp;#x27;ll be ready for:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Security and Risk Management&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Asset Security&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Security Architecture and Engineering&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Communication and Network Security&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Identity and Access Management (IAM)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Security Assessment and Testing&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Security Operations&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Software Development Security&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;</description><enclosure url="https://learning.oreilly.com/library/cover/9781394254699/" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Python Crash Course, 3rd Edition 👨‍🏫 Eric Matthes 📅 2023-01-10</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/library/view/python-crash-course/9781098156664/</link><description>&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;Python Crash Course&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; is the world&amp;#x27;s best-selling guide to the Python guide programming language, with over 1,500,000 copies sold to date!&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This fast-paced, thorough introduction to programming with Python will have you writing code, solving problems, and making cool projects that work in no time.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;In the first half of the book, you&amp;#x27;ll learn basic programming concepts, such as variables, lists, loops, and classes, and practice writing clean code with exercises for each topic. You&amp;#x27;ll also learn how to make your programs interactive and test your code safely before adding it to a project. In the second half, you&amp;#x27;ll put your new knowledge into practice with three substantial projects: a Space Invaders--inspired arcade game, a set of data visualizations with Python&amp;#x27;s handy libraries, and a simple web app you can deploy online.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;As you work through the book, you&amp;#x27;ll learn how to:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;•Use powerful Python libraries and tools, including Pygame, Matplotlib, Plotly, and Django&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;•Make 2D games that respond to keypresses and mouse clicks&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;•Use data to generate interactive visualizations&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;•Create and customize web apps and deploy them safely online&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;•Deal with mistakes and errors so you can solve your own programming problems&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This updated third edition has been thoroughly revised to reflect the latest in Python code and practices. The first half of the book includes improved coverage of topics like variables, handling errors, and object-oriented programming. In the second half, the code for the projects has been updated with current example data, better app deployment, and up-to-date libraries and tools, like Plotly, the Tailwind CSS framework, and the latest version of Django.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;If you&amp;#x27;ve been thinking about digging into programming, &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;Python Crash Course&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; will get you writing real programs fast. Why wait any longer? Start your engines and code!&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;</description><enclosure url="https://learning.oreilly.com/library/cover/9781098156664/" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>System Design on AWS 👨‍🏫 Jayanth Kumar, Mandeep Singh 📅 2025-02-21</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/library/view/system-design-on/9781098146887/</link><description>&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Enterprises building complex and large-scale applications in the cloud face multiple challenges. From figuring out the right tools to estimating the right provisioning, nearly every solution comes with a complicated set of choices and trade-offs. AWS provides a one-stop shop for building and scaling these applications, and this practical guide helps you decide which pieces to use and how to fit them together. 
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
Authors Jayanth Kumar and Mandeep Singh equip software architects and engineers with essential AWS and system design knowledge to help you make good decisions and overcome the challenges of designing and scaling enterprise software architecture. By diving into specific use cases, you&amp;#x27;ll understand how these principles and resources can be applied to real-world problems. 
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
With this book, you will:
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Learn the basics and best practices of successful system design
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Understand key AWS services and their strengths and limitations for building large-scale systems
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Examine engineering patterns and principles that best support large-scale systems, and learn how to design architecture with scalability, operations, and resilience in mind
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Learn what highly performant and cost-optimized architectures look like on AWS and the tools and frameworks that are best for specific use cases
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;</description><enclosure url="https://learning.oreilly.com/library/cover/9781098146887/" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Learning Go, 2nd Edition 👨‍🏫 Jon Bodner 📅 2024-01-11</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/library/view/learning-go-2nd/9781098139285/</link><description>&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Go has rapidly become the preferred language for building web services. Plenty of tutorials are available to teach Go&amp;#x27;s syntax to developers with experience in other programming languages, but tutorials aren&amp;#x27;t enough. They don&amp;#x27;t teach Go&amp;#x27;s idioms, so developers end up recreating patterns that don&amp;#x27;t make sense in a Go context. This practical guide provides the essential background you need to write clear and idiomatic Go.
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
No matter your level of experience, you&amp;#x27;ll learn how to think like a Go developer. Author Jon Bodner introduces the design patterns experienced Go developers have adopted and explores the rationale for using them. This updated edition also shows you how Go&amp;#x27;s generics support fits into the language.
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
This book helps you:
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Write idiomatic code in Go and design a Go project
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Understand the reasons behind Go&amp;#x27;s design decisions 
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Set up a Go development environment for a solo developer or team
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Learn how and when to use reflection, unsafe, and cgo
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Discover how Go&amp;#x27;s features allow the language to run efficiently
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Know which Go features you should use sparingly or not at all
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Use Go&amp;#x27;s tools to improve performance, optimize memory usage, and reduce garbage collection
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Learn how to use Go&amp;#x27;s advanced development tools
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;</description><enclosure url="https://learning.oreilly.com/library/cover/9781098139285/" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Building Applications with AI Agents 👨‍🏫 Michael Albada 📅 2025-09-23</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/library/view/building-applications-with/9781098176495/</link><description>&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Generative AI has revolutionized how organizations tackle problems, accelerating the journey from concept to prototype to solution. As the models become increasingly capable, we have witnessed a new design pattern emerge: AI agents. By combining tools, knowledge, memory, and learning with advanced foundation models, we can now sequence multiple model inferences together to solve ambiguous and difficult problems. From coding agents to research agents to analyst agents and more, we&amp;#x27;ve already seen agents accelerate teams and organizations. While these agents enhance efficiency, they often require extensive planning, drafting, and revising to complete complex tasks, and deploying them remains a challenge for many organizations, especially as technology and research rapidly develops.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This book is your indispensable guide through this intricate and fast-moving landscape. Author Michael Albada provides a practical and research-based approach to designing and implementing single- and multiagent systems. It simplifies the complexities and equips you with the tools to move from concept to solution efficiently.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Understand the distinct features of foundation model-enabled AI agents
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Discover the core components and design principles of AI agents
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Explore design trade-offs and implement effective multiagent systems
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Design and deploy tailored AI solutions, enhancing efficiency and innovation in your field
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;</description><enclosure url="https://learning.oreilly.com/library/cover/9781098176495/" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>LLM Engineer's Handbook 👨‍🏫 Paul Iusztin, Maxime Labonne 📅 2024-10-22</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/library/view/llm-engineers-handbook/9781836200079/</link><description>&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The &amp;quot;LLM Engineer&amp;#x27;s Handbook&amp;quot; is your comprehensive guide to mastering Large Language Models from concept to deployment. Written by leading experts, it combines theoretical foundations with practical examples to help you build, refine, and deploy LLM-powered solutions that solve real-world problems effectively and efficiently.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;What this Book will help me do&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Understand the principles and approaches for training and fine-tuning Large Language Models (LLMs).&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Apply MLOps practices to design, deploy, and monitor your LLM applications effectively.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Implement advanced techniques such as retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) and preference alignment.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Optimize inference for high performance, addressing low-latency and high availability for production systems.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Develop robust data pipelines and scalable architectures for building modular LLM systems.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Author(s)&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Paul Iusztin and Maxime Labonne are experienced AI professionals specializing in natural language processing and machine learning. With years of industry and academic experience, they are dedicated to making complex AI concepts accessible and actionable. Their collaborative authorship ensures a blend of theoretical rigor and practical insights tailored for modern AI practitioners.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Who is it for?&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This book is tailored for AI engineers, NLP professionals, and LLM practitioners who wish to deepen their understanding of Large Language Models. Ideal readers possess some familiarity with Python, AWS, and general AI concepts. If you aim to apply LLMs to real-world scenarios or enhance your expertise in AI-driven systems, this handbook is designed for you.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;</description><enclosure url="https://learning.oreilly.com/library/cover/9781836200079/" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Learning LangChain 👨‍🏫 Mayo Oshin, Nuno Campos 📅 2025-02-14</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/library/view/learning-langchain/9781098167271/</link><description>&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;If you&amp;#x27;re looking to build production-ready AI applications that can reason and retrieve external data for context-awareness, you&amp;#x27;ll need to master--;a popular development framework and platform for building, running, and managing agentic applications. LangChain is used by several leading companies, including Zapier, Replit, Databricks, and many more. This guide is an indispensable resource for developers who understand Python or JavaScript but are beginners eager to harness the power of AI.

&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Authors Mayo Oshin and Nuno Campos demystify the use of LangChain through practical insights and in-depth tutorials. Starting with basic concepts, this book shows you step-by-step how to build a production-ready AI agent that uses your data.
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Harness the power of retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) to enhance the accuracy of LLMs using external up-to-date data
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Develop and deploy AI applications that interact intelligently and contextually with users
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Make use of the powerful agent architecture with LangGraph 
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Integrate and manage third-party APIs and tools to extend the functionality of your AI applications
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Monitor, test, and evaluate your AI applications to improve performance
&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Understand the foundations of LLM app development and how they can be used with LangChain&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;</description><enclosure url="https://learning.oreilly.com/library/cover/9781098167271/" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>Fundamentals of Data Engineering 👨‍🏫 Joe Reis, Matt Housley 📅 2022-06-22</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/library/view/fundamentals-of-data/9781098108298/</link><description>&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Data engineering has grown rapidly in the past decade, leaving many software engineers, data scientists, and analysts looking for a comprehensive view of this practice. With this practical book, you&amp;#x27;ll learn how to plan and build systems to serve the needs of your organization and customers by evaluating the best technologies available through the framework of the data engineering lifecycle.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Authors Joe Reis and Matt Housley walk you through the data engineering lifecycle and show you how to stitch together a variety of cloud technologies to serve the needs of downstream data consumers. You&amp;#x27;ll understand how to apply the concepts of data generation, ingestion, orchestration, transformation, storage, and governance that are critical in any data environment regardless of the underlying technology.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This book will help you:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Get a concise overview of the entire data engineering landscape&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Assess data engineering problems using an end-to-end framework of best practices&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Cut through marketing hype when choosing data technologies, architecture, and processes&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Use the data engineering lifecycle to design and build a robust architecture&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Incorporate data governance and security across the data engineering lifecycle&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;</description><enclosure url="https://learning.oreilly.com/library/cover/9781098108298/" type="image/jpeg" /></item><item><title>React - The Complete Guide (Includes Hooks, React Router, and Redux) - Second Edition 👨‍🏫 Academind by Maximilian Schwarzmüller GmbH 📅 2024-04-30</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/videos/react-the/9781801812603/</link><description>&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;In this 64-hour course, you will master React from the basics to advanced concepts, enabling you to build scalable and efficient web applications. You&amp;#x27;ll explore fundamentals like components and state, while delving into complex topics such as routing, hooks, and state management with Redux.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;What I will be able to do after this course&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Develop scalable web applications using React and advanced frameworks like Next.js.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Master state management techniques with Redux, Context API, and useReducer.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Implement single-page application routing effectively with React Router.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Optimize React applications for better performance with advanced techniques.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Gain confidence in deploying and debugging React applications.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Course Instructor(s)&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Maximilian Schwarzmüller is an experienced software developer who specializes in web and mobile applications. With years of professional experience and a passion for teaching, he has guided thousands of learners on their journey to becoming skilled in coding. Max&amp;#x27;s approach is hands-on and project-based, ensuring that students walk away with practical, employable skills.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Who is it for?&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This course is ideal for aspiring web developers and software engineers who want to learn React from scratch or improve their React skills. Beginners with basic knowledge of JavaScript will gain a strong foundation, while advanced developers can deepen their knowledge in modern React features. Perfect for anyone seeking a comprehensive guide to mastering React.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong id=&amp;quot;content-levels&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Content Level: Intermediate&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong id=&amp;quot;has_quiz&amp;quot;&amp;gt;With Quizzes&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong id=&amp;quot;has_badge&amp;quot;&amp;gt;With Badge&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;</description><enclosure url="https://learning.oreilly.com/library/cover/9781801812603/" type="image/jpeg" /></item></channel></rss>