<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>O'Reilly - Recent Software Development Courses</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/</link><description>Latest software development courses from O'Reilly Online Learning.</description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 16:07:58 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title>Software Engineering at Google</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/api/v1/book/9781492082781/</link><description>Today, software engineers need to know not only how to program effectively but also how to develop proper engineering practices to make their codebase sustainable and healthy. This book emphasizes this difference between programming and software engineering. How can software engineers manage a living codebase that evolves and responds to changing r...</description><pubDate>2020-03-03T00:00:00Z</pubDate></item><item><title>Balancing Coupling in Software Design: Universal Design Principles for Architecting Modular Software Systems</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/api/v1/book/9780137353514/</link><description>Learn How Coupling Impacts Every Software Design Decision You Make--and How to Control ItIf you want to build modular, evolvable, and resilient software systems, you have to get coupling right. Every design decision you make influences coupling, which in turn shapes the design options available to you. Despite its importance, coupling often doesn't...</description><pubDate>2023-10-28T00:00:00Z</pubDate></item><item><title>Software Development Superstream: Generative AI to Improve Software Development</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/api/v1/book/0642572008390/</link><description>Sponsored by TabnineChatGPT and similar tools have made their mark on software development. Understanding how to work with generative AI is now a core skill for almost every software developer.Join us to discover how to use generative AI to benefit the software development lifecycle. You’ll explore available AI tools that can help with common devel...</description><pubDate>2024-10-02T00:00:00Z</pubDate></item><item><title>Righting Software</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/api/v1/book/9780136524007/</link><description>Right Your Software and Transform Your CareerRighting Software presents the proven, structured, and highly engineered approach to software design that renowned architect Juval Löwy has practiced and taught around the world. Although companies of every kind have successfully implemented his original design ideas across hundreds of systems, these ins...</description><pubDate>2019-12-10T00:00:00Z</pubDate></item><item><title>Follow the Money</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/api/v1/book/9798341661349/</link><description>Why do great engineers and team leads stumble when scaling up? Why do thriving businesses fumble large-scale technical transformations? At its core, a business is a way of managing how money enters, circulates, and leaves an organization. Yet most software engineers stick to code and architecture, overlooking the financial and organizational struct...</description><pubDate>2026-12-25T00:00:00Z</pubDate></item><item><title>The Nature of Software Development</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/api/v1/book/9781680500721/</link><description>You need to get value from your software project. You need it "free, now, and perfect." We can't get you there, but we can help you get to "cheaper, sooner, and better." This book leads you from the desire for value down to the specific activities that help good Agile projects deliver better software sooner, and at a lower cost. Using simple sketch...</description><pubDate>2015-02-19T00:00:00Z</pubDate></item><item><title>OSCON Open Source Software Superstream Series: Live Coding—Go, Rust, and Python</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/api/v1/book/0636920455653/</link><description>Watch Part 2, OSCON Open Source Software Superstream Series: Cloud Strategies and Implementation.Watch Part 3, OSCON Open Source Software Superstream Series: Infrastructure.This three-part series of half-day online events gives attendees an overarching perspective of software development from which to make decisions that strengthen and grow compani...</description><pubDate>2020-06-24T00:00:00Z</pubDate></item><item><title>Working with Coders: A Guide to Software Development for the Perplexed Non-Techie</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/api/v1/book/9781484227008/</link><description>Get introduced to the fascinating world inhabited by the professional software developer. Aimed at a non-technical audience, this book aims to de-obfuscate the jargon, explain the various activities that coders undertake, and analyze the specific pressures, priorities, and preoccupations that developers are prone to. In each case it offers pragmati...</description><pubDate>2017-07-05T00:00:00Z</pubDate></item><item><title>Seriously Good Software video edition</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/api/v1/book/9781617296291VE/</link><description>In Video Editions the narrator reads the book while the content, figures, code listings, diagrams, and text appear on the screen. Like an audiobook that you can also watch as a video. Building high-quality software is never simple, and it is always a good idea to reexamine the principles of good design and craftsmanship. In this book, you will find...</description><pubDate>2020-03-20T00:00:00Z</pubDate></item><item><title>Peopleware: Productive Projects and Teams, Third Edition</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/api/v1/book/9780133440706/</link><description>Few books in computing have had as profound an influence on software management as Peopleware. The unique insight of this longtime best seller is that the major issues of software development are human, not technical. They’re not easy issues; but solve them, and you’ll maximize your chances of success. “Peopleware has long been one of my two favori...</description><pubDate>2013-06-18T00:00:00Z</pubDate></item></channel></rss>