<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>O'Reilly Developer Courses</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/</link><description>Latest developer courses from O'Reilly</description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 08:52:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>OSCON 2019 - Portland, Oregon</title><link>/videos/oscon-2019/9781492050643/</link><description>&lt;div&gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;OSCON Portland 2019 brought together a vibrant and diverse collection of talented speakers (open source leaders from around the globe) who do amazing things with open source technologies. This outstanding group provided the conference attendees (thousands of software developers, programmers, architects, engineers, CxOs, hackers, geeks, and analysts) with the opportunity to explore the latest open source tools and technologies; get expert in-depth training in crucial languages, frameworks, and best practices; and gain exposure to the open source stack in all its possible configurations.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This video compilation offers you the chance to see and hear the best of OSCON Portland 2019. If you want to know how to build an open source culture at your company, work in a cloud environment that isn&amp;#x27;t always open source-friendly, understand how machine learning can make or break your code, or implement new technologies like Kubernetes and TensorFlow, then getting the OSCON Portland 2019 video compilation is for you.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Highlights include:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Complete video recordings of OSCON Portland 2019’s best keynotes, tutorials, and tech sessions offering hours of material to study and absorb at your own pace and schedule&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Keynotes, including Adam Jacob (Chef) on the war for the soul of open source; Kay Williams (Microsoft Azure) on lessons learned building a strong Kubernetes/VSCode open source community; Adrian Cockcroft (AWS) on leveraging cloud vendors to boost open source business success; and Pete Skomoroch (Workday) on the urgent need for a new open source ML development stack&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Tutorials offering deep dives into open source tech like Apache Kafka, Rust, extended Berkeley Packet Filters, Spring/Spring Boot, Ethereum DApps, Jenkins 2, Vault/Kubernetes, and Kubeflow&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;The OSCON Business Summit: sessions offering an insider’s look at the open source implementations that have the most profound impact on business with talks by open source specialists at Uber, Pacific Life, Verizon Media, The Home Depot, Baidu, the BBC, and more&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Open Source do-it-now sessions, including Deb Nicholson’s (Software Freedom Conservancy) whirlwind tour of what not to do when running an open source project; Russell Rutledge’s (Nike) take on how to build an open source culture at your company; and Angie Jones (Applitools) and a panel of experts from Persea Consulting, Red Hat, Magento, and ForgeRock on the best ways to build and maintain open source communities&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Emerging Languages and Frameworks sessions, such as Josh Long (Pivotal) on what the Spring and Kotlin teams do to ensure that app development on the Java virtual machine can fly fast and safe; Sander Mak’s (Luminis Technologies) review of everything that&amp;#x27;s happened between Java 8 and Java 12; and Sam Lanning (Semmle Inc) on how TypeScript is transforming the JavaScript ecosystem&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Incorporating AI sessions, including Julien Simon (Amazon Web Services) on how to build ML inference pipelines using open source libraries and scale them on AWS; Holden Karau (Google) and Trevor Grant (IBM) on how to build ML models and set up serving across clouds with Kubeflow; and Sam Charrington’s (podcast host, “This Week in Machine Learning &amp;amp;amp; AI”) review of the best practices for delivering ML infrastructure and the landscape of available open source solutions&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Sessions from luminaries such as Jon Galloway (.NET Foundation) on what open source foundations do and why they matter; Alison McCauley, author of “Unblocked: How Blockchains Will Change Your Business” on what the blockchain future will actually look like; and VM Brasseur’s (Juniper Networks) sold out tips, tricks, and stuff-that-works session on how to plow through the often demoralizing process of finding a new job&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt; 👨‍🏫 Author(s): O&amp;#x27;Reilly Media, Inc. 📅 Released: 2019-07-17T00:00:00Z</description></item><item><title>Observability at Google</title><link>/videos/observability-at-google/0636920424239/</link><description>&lt;div&gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Google has been doing microservices observability for more than a decade. Jaana Burcu Dogan outlines key approaches in instrumenting Google&amp;#x27;s services, shares best practices and lessons learned related to patterns, UX, performance, and security, and discusses the company&amp;#x27;s recent work to open-source its internal stack.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt; 👨‍🏫 Author(s): Jaana B. Dogan 📅 Released: 2019-09-16T00:00:00Z</description></item><item><title>OSCON 2018 - Portland, Oregon</title><link>/videos/oscon-2018/9781492026075/</link><description>&lt;div&gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;quot;When we give away our software, we create value,&amp;quot; says Tim O&amp;#x27;Reilly (O&amp;#x27;Reilly Media) when describing the core of the open source philosophy.  And nothing demonstrates the validity of Tim&amp;#x27;s statement more than the keynotes, tutorials, and technical sessions delivered by the speakers at OSCON Portland 2018. OSCON Portland 2018 was organized into many value-adding content tracks, with each track selected for its significance to software development and solving critical real-world problems. This video compilation gives you total access to each track and to virtually every session, tutorial, and keynote delivered over this four-day event. Highlights include:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Live coding: New to OSCON, these sessions demonstrated coding best practices and new ways of getting the most out of open source languages like Python, R, Java, and C#. In this video, you&amp;#x27;ll hear the presenters speak as the code they write appears on your screen. Includes Joel Grus (Allen Institute for Artificial Intelligence) live-coding a deep learning library from scratch using NumPy and Eve Porcello (Moon Highway) live-coding a walk-through of GraphQL, and more.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Business Summit: Designed specifically for executives, business leaders, and strategists, the Business Summit featured high-level case studies showcasing the most successful developments in open source for the enterprise. Learn how to mitigate risk and out-innovate your competitors from speakers like Greg Taylor (Reddit), Daniel Ruggeri (Mastercard), and Eddie Satterly (DataNexus).&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Emerging languages: Hear about open source&amp;#x27;s best and brightest new languages. Includes Timirah James&amp;#x27;s (Independent) overview of using Swift to build servers and apps, plus tutorials on Go, Kotlin, Godot, and JavaScript development&amp;#x27;s GRANDstack (GraphQL, React, Apollo, and Neo4).&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;TensorFlow: Includes a machine learning how-to by Josh Gordon (Google) and everything from the TensorFlow Community Day event, with talks by Google TensorFlow&amp;#x27;s product team and by TensorFlow practitioners in health care, gaming, and more.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Blockchain: Open source blockchain will be a game-changer in how we deliver data. Includes Lucy Wyman&amp;#x27;s (Puppet) primer on blockchain technology and Mack Hendricks&amp;#x27;s (CEO, Flyball) session on using blockchain technology to stop fraudulent calls on telephone caller ID systems.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Cloud strategies and implementation: Discover how cloud strategies and implementations impact business. Includes talks by Jessica Deen (Microsoft) on container orchestration and Nathan Handler (Yelp) on Hashicorp&amp;#x27;s Terraform, plus tutorials on continuous delivery with Spinnaker by Emily Burns (Netflix).&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Artificial intelligence: Learn about the open source frameworks that have taken AI to a new dimension with sessions and tutorials on Apache MXNet, OpenCV, Vision/Core ML, Python-based natural language processing, the 2D graphics library Skia, and how to power TensorFlow with big data using Apache Beam, Flink and Spark.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Evolutionary architecture: Understand why architectures, like microservices and serverless, are necessary in the time of continuous development and delivery. Includes tutorials and sessions like &amp;quot;.NET Core 2.0: From acquisition to containers&amp;quot; (Shayne Boyer, Microsoft), &amp;quot;Open source data persistence: creating order from chaos&amp;quot; (Megan Kostick, Michael Brewer, Manuel Silveyra; IBM)  and &amp;quot;Fundamentals of GraphQL&amp;quot; (Danilo Zekovic, Symphony).&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Offering a front row seat for each of OSCON Portland&amp;#x27;s keynotes, tutorials, and technical sessions, this video compilation delivers true value.  Get it now to experience Portland OSCON 2018 according to your own schedule and pace.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt; 👨‍🏫 Author(s): O&amp;#x27;Reilly Media, Inc. 📅 Released: 2018-07-18T00:00:00Z</description></item><item><title>Software Development, Design, and Coding: With Patterns, Debugging, Unit Testing, and Refactoring</title><link>/library/view/software-development-design/9798868802850/</link><description>&lt;div&gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Learn the principles of good software design and then turn those principles into great code. This book introduces you to software engineering — from the application of engineering principles to the development of software. You&amp;#x27;ll see how to run a software development project, examine the different phases of a project, and learn how to design and implement programs that solve specific problems. This book is also about code construction — how to write great programs and make them work. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This new third edition is revamped to reflect significant changes in the software development landscape with updated design and coding examples and figures. Extreme programming takes a backseat, making way for expanded coverage of the most crucial agile methodologies today: Scrum, Lean Software Development, Kanban, and Dark Scrum. Agile principles are revised to explore further functionalities of requirement gathering. The authors venture beyond imperative and object-oriented languages, exploring the realm of scripting languages in an expanded chapter on Code Construction. The Project Management Essentials chapter has been revamped and expanded to incorporate &amp;quot;SoftAware Development” to discuss the crucial interpersonal nature of joint software creation.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Whether you&amp;#x27;re new to programming or have written hundreds of applications, in this book you&amp;#x27;ll re-examine what you already do, and you&amp;#x27;ll investigate ways to improve. Using the Java language, you&amp;#x27;ll look deeply into coding standards, debugging, unit testing, modularity, and other characteristics of good programs.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;You Will Learn&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Modern agile methodologies&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;How to work on and with development teams&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;How to leverage the capabilities of modern computer systems with parallel programming&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;How to work with design patterns to exploit application development best practices&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;How to use modern tools for development, collaboration, and source code controls&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Who This Book Is For&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Early career software developers, or upper-level students in software engineering courses&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt; 👨‍🏫 Author(s): John F. Dooley, Vera A. Kazakova 📅 Released: 2024-06-27T00:00:00Z</description></item><item><title>The Software Craftsman: Professionalism, Pragmatism, Pride</title><link>/library/view/the-software-craftsman/9780134052625/</link><description>&lt;div&gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Be a Better Developer and Deliver Better Code&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Despite advanced tools and methodologies, software projects continue to fail. Why? Too many organizations still view software development as just another production line. Too many developers feel that way, too—and they behave accordingly.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;In &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;The Software Craftsman: Professionalism, Pragmatism, Pride,&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; Sandro Mancuso offers a better and more fulfilling path. If you want to develop software with pride and professionalism; love what you do and do it with excellence; and build a career with autonomy, mastery, and purpose, it starts with the recognition that you are a craftsman. Once you embrace this powerful mindset, you can achieve unprecedented levels of technical excellence and customer satisfaction.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Mancuso helped found the world’s largest organization of software craftsmen; now, he shares what he’s learned through inspiring examples and pragmatic advice you can use in your company, your projects, and your career.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You will learn&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Why agile processes aren’t enough and why craftsmanship is crucial to making them work&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;How craftsmanship helps you build software right and helps clients in ways that go beyond code&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;How and when to say “No” and how to provide creative alternatives when you do&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Why bad code happens to good developers and how to stop creating and justifying it&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;How to make working with legacy code less painful and more productive&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;How to be pragmatic—not dogmatic—about your practices and tools&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;How to lead software craftsmen and attract them to your organization&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;What to avoid when advertising positions, interviewing candidates, and hiring developers&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;How developers and their managers can create a true culture of learning&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;How to drive true technical change and overcome deep patterns of skepticism&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Sandro Mancuso&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; has coded for startups, software houses, product companies, international consultancies, and investment banks. In October 2013, he cofounded Codurance, a consultancy based on Software Craftsmanship principles and values. His involvement with Software Craftsmanship began in 2010, when he founded the London Software Craftsmanship Community (LSCC), now the world’s largest and most active Software Craftsmanship community, with more than two thousand craftsmen. For the past four years, he has inspired and helped developers to organize Software Craftsmanship communities throughout Europe, the United States, and the rest of the world.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt; 👨‍🏫 Author(s): Sandro Mancuso 📅 Released: 2014-12-14T00:00:00Z</description></item><item><title>Understanding Software</title><link>/library/view/understanding-software/9781788628815/</link><description>&lt;div&gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Understanding Software by Max Kanat-Alexander is an enlightening guide to simplifying programming and improving as a developer. With insights into simplicity as a design principle, Max shares lessons on debugging, team collaboration, and maintaining code health. This book equips you with the mindset and practices to code with clarity and purpose.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;What this Book will help me do&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Distinguish between complex and simple software design, enabling more maintainable code.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Adopt strategies to debug more effectively, improving development efficiency.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Gain insights into collaboration within developer teams, fostering better teamwork.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Understand causality in software complexity to make informed design choices.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Enhance your programming mindset to embrace simplicity as a core philosophy.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Author(s)&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Max Kanat-Alexander, known for his thoughtful approach to software development, serves as the Technical Lead for Code Health at Google. With a deep commitment to simplicity in programming, Max has inspired countless developers through his writings and lectures. His book brings together years of reflection and practical advice for achieving excellence in software engineering.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Who is it for?&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This book is ideal for software developers of all experience levels seeking to improve their coding practices and adopt simplicity in design. Whether you&amp;#x27;re a beginner looking to learn foundational mindsets or an experienced programmer in need of a fresh perspective, Understanding Software offers valuable insights. It&amp;#x27;s particularly suited to those striving to build maintainable, effective, and thoughtful code. If you&amp;#x27;re passionate about bettering yourself in programming and team collaboration, this book aligns with your ambitions.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt; 👨‍🏫 Author(s): Max Kanat-Alexander 📅 Released: 2017-09-29T00:00:00Z</description></item><item><title>Highlights from the Keynotes of OSCON Conference, Portland, 2019</title><link>/videos/highlights-from-the/0636920386544/</link><description>&lt;div&gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This curated collection of keynote highlights from the O&amp;#x27;Reilly Open Source Software Conference in Portland &amp;#x27;19 is full of useful insights and helpful guidance.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;For more content from this event, be sure to check out the &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://learning.oreilly.com/videos/oscon-2019/9781492050643/&amp;quot;&amp;gt;full conference video compilation&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt; 👨‍🏫 Author(s): Rachel Roumeliotis 📅 Released: 2020-04-09T00:00:00Z</description></item><item><title>Effective Software Development for the Enterprise: Beyond Domain Driven Design, Software Architecture, and Extreme Programming</title><link>/library/view/effective-software-development/9781484293850/</link><description>&lt;div&gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;It’s a jungle out there.&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;Delivering software solutions with predictable costs, time, scope, and quality has become more complicated than ever. Developers need to account for multiple moving targets, including often avoided but always relevant factors such as culture, people, and leadership. To effectively deal with these challenges, it’s necessary to rethink the entire delivery chain of modern software development. &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;This book addresses all these topics, putting everything in perspective, from the potential awkwardness created by cultural differences to connecting code with business outcomes to make delivering quality solutions possible. As a software engineer who strives to be his best and challenge the status quo when building IT systems, author Tengiz Tutisani always wanted a book that would cover all of these elements from a developer’s perspective — so he wrote one. &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;Effective Software Development for the Enterprise&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; builds on advanced disciplines, methodologies, and techniques derived from domain-driven design, software architecture, and extreme programming. Its objective is to aid modern software engineers and solution architects in building and delivering high-quality solutions for an enterprise while meeting ambitious criteria:&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Meet users&amp;#x27; expectations&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Deliver solutions on time with no defects&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Create products that can scale-out horizontally&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Solutions should not require a dedicated production support team&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Accelerate development pace&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Double ROI per developer, team, and software&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;You will learn how to achieve these objectives in any engineering environment by developing solid strategies based on the industry&amp;#x27;s well-known, recognized, and proven patterns and principles. After reading this book, you will be ready to effectively deal with any and all challenges posed by today’s hyper-competitive, globally-diverse, fast-moving enterprise environment.&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Who This Book Is For&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;Professional software engineers and solution architects, as well as those aspiring to become one. Additionally, software engineering leaders will benefit from reading it, as it will help them maximize their impact via successful software project deliveries.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt; 👨‍🏫 Author(s): Tengiz Tutisani 📅 Released: 2023-05-23T00:00:00Z</description></item><item><title>OSCON 2015: Video Compilation</title><link>/videos/oscon-2015-video/9781491927991/</link><description>&lt;div&gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;OSCON: leading the way for the evolving software community&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Not long ago, IT teams smuggled open source software through the back door and into production because these were the best tools for the job. Today, if you deconstructed your stack or took a survey of your favorite tools, you’d find a preponderance of open source software. Open source won.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;With this complete video compilation of OSCON 2015, you’ll learn about the latest developments, add to your skills, and discover how other people are solving the same problems you’re working on. Get a front row seat to every keynote, session, tutorial, and workshop from this year’s conference... and begin a new chapter in open source.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Explore, experience, and learn how all the pieces of the entire open source ecosystem go together&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Learn from the best and most original minds in your field, including creators of the tools and languages you&amp;#x27;re using&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Get solutions to your biggest challenges that you can apply today, from security to mobile devices and the cloud&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Hear about the latest research, best practices, technologies, and analytic approaches recently unveiled&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;See how start-ups, innovators, and some of the most successful companies have incorporated new developments, products, services, and career trends&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt; 👨‍🏫 Author(s): O&amp;#x27;Reilly Media, Inc. 📅 Released: 2015-08-11T00:00:00Z</description></item><item><title>OSCON 2016: Video Compilation</title><link>/videos/oscon-2016-video/9781491965153/</link><description>&lt;div&gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;OSCON Austin 2016 was as big as Texas itself with 293 speakers, 149 sessions, 40 half-day tutorials and 15 keynotes. An exploration of “Everything Open Source”, the four-day conference was organized into 12 distinct themes with multiple presentations on The New Stuff, Infrastructure, Architecture, Data, In Real Life, Collaboration, Business of OS, Open Source 101, Performance, Hardware, Security, and Leadership. Unsure about the core technologies of OS?  Where it’s headed? Don’t be. Get up on this video horse, push play, and ride. You’ll journey across the entire OS range from Linux, MySQL, the LAMP stack, Perl, Python and Ruby on Rails to middleware, applications, cloud computing, and more.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt; Enjoy an all-access pass to OSCON Austin 2016’s 15 keynotes, 40 tutorials, and 149 sessions&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;    Review the future of OS with Sam Ramji of Cloud Foundry and Pay Pal’s Danese Cooper&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;    Get the latest on microservices, Rust, and containers (Docker, Kubernetes, and Mesos)&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;  Discover the new: Perl 6, Go, Clojure,.NET Core, cloud-native Java apps, HTTP/2, and PHP/7&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt; Absorb ½ day tutorials on Git,  Scala, Neo4j, Ruby, Cassandra, R, ES6 + React, Tessel 2, and more&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;  Hear why Capital One, Salesforce.org, and Huawei chose OS - and why AOL returned&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;   Understand the challenges of OS: Patents, selling support, OS vs. proprietary, and more&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;    Explore 17 presentations each on OS architecture, OS infrastructure, and OS data&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;   Take in 8 presentations on OS hardware, 8 on OS performance, and 7 on OS security&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;  Download the videos or view them through our HD player&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt; 👨‍🏫 Author(s): O&amp;#x27;Reilly Media, Inc. 📅 Released: 2016-06-07T00:00:00Z</description></item></channel></rss>