<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>O'Reilly Courses - Software Development</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com</link><description>Latest O'Reilly courses about software development</description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:02:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Game Development with GameMaker: A Primer on Game Development and Design</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/library/view/game-development-with/9798868808791/</link><description>&lt;div&gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Create games from start to finish while learning game design and programming principles using the GameMaker. &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Game Development with GameMaker&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; covers all aspects of game design and development from the initial idea to the final release. You will learn how to make a 2D game from start to finish using GameMaker covering important features and topics related to game development. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The book will cover design and development of a top-down action game from start to finish leveraging on best practices according to the current state of the industry’s standards. It will cover all the building blocks of 2D game development: movements, combat, AI, UI, level design, inventory, power ups, etc. This edition also aims to implement the many changes that has come to GameMaker: new features as well as best practices.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;You Will&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Master GameMaker Language (GML) programming&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Apply game design principles and programming patterns&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Learn about 2D game development techniques and best practices&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Review the visual programming tool of GameMaker&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Who This Book is For&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Game enthusiasts interested in game development and design with GameMaker would benefit from the book. No prior programming experience is required.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;👨‍🏫 Author(s): Sebastiano M. Cossu&lt;br&gt;📅 Released: 2024-10-15T00:00:00Z&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Risk Management in Video Game Development</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/videos/risk-management-in/9781806101658/</link><description>&lt;div&gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;In this 8-hour course, you will master the essentials of risk management specifically tailored for video game development. The course includes real-world applications of risk management techniques to address game development challenges, such as budget, staffing, and scheduling. With a thorough exploration of each development stage, you&amp;#x27;ll gain the ability to ensure project success.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;What I will be able to do after this course&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Analyze and identify common risks in video game development projects.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Develop and implement strategies to mitigate identified risks effectively.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Utilize tools and methods, such as Miro, to manage risk tracking and communication.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Adapt risk management strategies for each stage of the game development lifecycle.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Foster and maintain a proactive and risk-aware development team culture.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Course Instructor(s)&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The instructor has extensive experience in the video game industry, focusing on production management and agile methodologies. With a passion for empowering teams, they have taught professionals effective risk management practices through accessible and engaging instruction. Their insights are driven by field experience and a commitment to fostering success.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Who is it for?&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This course is tailored for video game developers, project managers, and team leads seeking to enhance their risk management skills. It also caters to roles such as QA testers and product managers involved in game development processes. A foundational knowledge of video game development is useful but not mandatory.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong id=&amp;quot;content-levels&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Content Level: Intermediate&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong id=&amp;quot;has_badge&amp;quot;&amp;gt;With Badge&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;👨‍🏫 Author(s): Eduonix Learning Solutions&lt;br&gt;📅 Released: 2025-06-16T00:00:00Z&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Intro to 3D Game Development Masterclass in Godot</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/videos/intro-to-3d/9781806119097/</link><description>&lt;div&gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;In this 11 hr course, you&amp;#x27;ll embark on a journey to master 3D game development using the Godot engine. From building dynamic environments to scripting interaction and creating gameplay systems, this course provides hands-on training to craft a complete 3D action-adventure prototype.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;What I will be able to do after this course&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Learn to design immersive 3D environments equipped with interactive elements.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Master character movement and physics interactions for dynamic gameplay.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Create menus and HUDs for user-friendly interfaces.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Develop combat mechanics complete with enemy AI and animations.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Implement inventory systems with usable and customizable items.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Course Instructor(s)&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Eduonix Learning Solutions features a team of experienced educators and developers passionate about making technical skills accessible. With expertise in game development and teaching, they provide clear instructions complemented by practical, real-world examples. Their engaging project-based approach ensures a productive and enjoyable learning experience.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Who is it for?&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This course best suits aspiring game developers aiming to enter the field of 3D development, especially those with a basic understanding of programming. Learners may come from 2D game development backgrounds or be completely new to game engines like Godot. It offers both foundational and advanced topics, equipping developers with the skills needed to craft professional games.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong id=&amp;quot;content-levels&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Content Level: Beginner, Intermediate&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong id=&amp;quot;has_badge&amp;quot;&amp;gt;With Badge&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;👨‍🏫 Author(s): Eduonix Learning Solutions&lt;br&gt;📅 Released: 2025-06-09T00:00:00Z&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Game Development Concepts in C++: Elevate Your Skills with Unreal Engine</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/library/view/game-development-concepts/9798868813993/</link><description>&lt;div&gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;MsoNormal&amp;quot; style=&amp;quot;mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; line-height: normal;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Leverage Unreal Engine to implement a wide variety of mechanics using C++. This book arms you with the knowledge and practices of game mechanics programming in C++, supported by detailed mathematical and programmatic explanations.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;MsoNormal&amp;quot; style=&amp;quot;mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; line-height: normal;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Detailing everything from collision mechanics and AI pathfinding to networking and advanced physics, this book offers a holistic approach to game development, ensuring you get the most out of your gameplay experiences. You will work on character mechanics, environmental interactions, combat systems, and visual effects, gaining a thorough understanding of how to implement these features in C++. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;MsoNormal&amp;quot; style=&amp;quot;mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; line-height: normal;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;By the time you finish this book, you will be able to create complex game mechanics and to make your projects optimization-intensive and performance-driven. Whether you want to polish your skills or experiment with new techniques, &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Game Dev Concepts in C++ for Unreal Engine Practitioners&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; gives you the right guidance and helps you to stand out in this competitive world of game development.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;MsoNormal&amp;quot; style=&amp;quot;mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; line-height: normal;&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;What You Will Learn&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li class=&amp;quot;MsoNormal&amp;quot; style=&amp;quot;line-height: normal;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Understand detailed scenarios that demonstrate how each mechanic is applied in real-world game development projects.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li class=&amp;quot;MsoNormal&amp;quot; style=&amp;quot;line-height: normal;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Utilize ready template codes for quicker implementation of mechanics in your games, saving time, and boosting productivity.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li class=&amp;quot;MsoNormal&amp;quot; style=&amp;quot;line-height: normal;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Develop your skills in advanced Unreal Engine and C++ programming, making you a versatile and proficient game developer.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li class=&amp;quot;MsoNormal&amp;quot; style=&amp;quot;line-height: normal;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;See how different mechanics work together to create engaging gameplay experiences.&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;MsoNormal&amp;quot; style=&amp;quot;mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; line-height: normal;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Who Is This Book For &amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p class=&amp;quot;MsoNormal&amp;quot; style=&amp;quot;mso-margin-top-alt: auto; mso-margin-bottom-alt: auto; line-height: normal;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Ideal for intermediate level game developers who have an understanding of Unreal Engine and have a set of basic programming skills in C++.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;👨‍🏫 Author(s): Sheikh Sohel Moon&lt;br&gt;📅 Released: 2025-07-04T00:00:00Z&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Game Boy Coding Adventure</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/library/view/game-boy-coding/0642572230166/</link><description>&lt;div&gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;Game Boy Coding Adventure&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; is a hands-on guide to programming one of the most iconic consoles ever built. And there is magic here: By leveraging the simplified assembly language of this retro machine, you’ll learn how to control every aspect of the Game Boy’s 8-bit hardware.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;As you build tile-based graphics, sprite animations, sound effects, input handling, timers, and more, you’ll discover how hardware behaves­—and how software components work together to run interactive programs. Along the way, you’ll gain a strong foundation in systems programming, mastering concepts like memory management, registers, interrupts, and I/O.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You’ll learn how to:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Write and debug assembly using RGBDS, the standard development toolchain&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Work with tiles, sprites, backgrounds, windows, and color palettes&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Control sound channels, interrupts, timers, frame pacing, and the joypad&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Leverage memory banking, DMA, and serial communication for more complex game features&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Experiment with the Super Game Boy, Game Boy Color, and the Game Boy Printer&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Written by a veteran game developer with over 15 years of experience building graphics engines and shipping titles across PC, mobile, and consoles, this book teaches more than just syntax. It takes you back to a simpler platform with a reduced instruction set that’s perfect for learning. You’ll write assembly code that runs directly on real hardware, see the results immediately, and learn how to debug, optimize, and control every cycle. You’ll also build game-ready components and develop a clear understanding of how software and hardware interact.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Why stop now? Slot in the cartridge, flip the switch, and start coding.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;👨‍🏫 Author(s): Maximilien Dagois&lt;br&gt;📅 Released: 2025-10-28T00:00:00Z&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Godot 4 for Beginners</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/library/view/godot-4-for/9781836203094/</link><description>&lt;div&gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;quot;Godot 4 for Beginners&amp;quot; empowers new game developers to effortlessly navigate through the features of Godot 4 and create engaging video games. By the end of the book, you&amp;#x27;ll feel confident in your ability to design dynamic 2D and 3D game environments, write efficient scripts in GDScript, and bring your creative game ideas to life.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;What this Book will help me do&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Install and set up the Godot 4 game engine on your device.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Understand and navigate Godot&amp;#x27;s interface to streamline your workflow.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Compose games using nodes and scenes for a scalable gaming architecture.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Create visually stunning 2D and 3D game environments.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Write scripts in GDScript to add interactivity and logic to your games.&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Author(s)&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Robert Henning, the author, is a game development educator with years of experience teaching and creating engaging game tutorials. He leverages his deep understanding of Godot 4 and approachable teaching style to simplify complex concepts. Robert has a passion for helping beginner game developers excel in the world of game creation.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Who is it for?&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This book is perfect for beginners to game development or people new to the Godot engine. Whether you are a student, hobbyist, or aspiring indie game developer, this guide will give you a robust introduction. Basic computer skills are required, and while knowledge of programming fundamentals can be helpful, no prior coding experience is necessary, as the book covers key programming concepts.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;👨‍🏫 Author(s): Robert Henning&lt;br&gt;📅 Released: 2025-08-20T00:00:00Z&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Linux and Open Source Software in Azure</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/library/view/linux-and-open/9781098178284/</link><description>&lt;div&gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;If you&amp;#x27;re an IT professional looking to expand your understanding of how Azure supports Linux and open source software (OSS), you&amp;#x27;ll need a resource that clearly explains how to leverage Azure to run, secure, monitor, and protect workloads. This report provides just that. 
&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;You&amp;#x27;ll discover the benefits of running Linux distributions like Azure Linux, Ubuntu, CentOS, and Red Hat Enterprise Linux on Azure and learn how to leverage Azure services to optimize your Linux and OSS workloads for security, scalability, and performance.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;👨‍🏫 Author(s): Adrián González Sánchez&lt;br&gt;📅 Released: 2024-11-25T00:00:00Z&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ghidra Software Reverse-Engineering for Beginners - Second Edition</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/library/view/ghidra-software-reverse-engineering/9781835889824/</link><description>&lt;div&gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Learn how to use Ghidra to analyze your code for potential vulnerabilities and examine both malware and network threats&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h4&amp;gt;Key Features&amp;lt;/h4&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Make the most of Ghidra on different platforms such as Linux, Windows, and macOS&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Unlock the potential of plug-ins and extensions for disassembly, assembly, decompilation, and scripting&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Learn advanced concepts like binary diffing, debugging, unpacking real-world malware samples, and reverse engineering ransomware&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Purchase of the print or Kindle book includes a free PDF eBook&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h4&amp;gt;Book Description&amp;lt;/h4&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Written by David Álvarez Pérez, a senior malware analyst at Gen Digital Inc., and Ravikant Tiwari, a senior security researcher at Microsoft, with expertise in malware and threat detection, this book is a complete guide to using Ghidra for examining malware, making patches, and customizing its features for your cybersecurity needs.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
This updated edition walks you through implementing Ghidra’s capabilities and automating reverse-engineering tasks with its plugins. You’ll learn how to set up an environment for practical malware analysis, use Ghidra in headless mode, and leverage Ghidra scripting to automate vulnerability detection in executable binaries. Advanced topics such as creating Ghidra plugins, adding new binary formats, analyzing processor modules, and contributing to the Ghidra project are thoroughly covered too.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
This edition also simplifies complex concepts such as remote and kernel debugging and binary diffing, and their practical uses, especially in malware analysis. From unpacking malware to analyzing modern ransomware, you’ll acquire the skills necessary for handling real-world cybersecurity challenges.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;
By the end of this Ghidra book, you’ll be adept at avoiding potential vulnerabilities in code, extending Ghidra for advanced reverse-engineering, and applying your skills to strengthen your cybersecurity strategies.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h4&amp;gt;What you will learn&amp;lt;/h4&amp;gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Develop and integrate your own Ghidra extensions&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Discover how to use Ghidra in headless mode&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Extend Ghidra for advanced reverse-engineering&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Perform binary differencing for use cases such as patch and vulnerability analysis&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Perform debugging locally and in a remote environment&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Apply your skills to real-world malware analysis scenarios including ransomware analysis and unpacking malware&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Automate vulnerability detection in executable binaries using Ghidra scripting&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&amp;lt;h4&amp;gt;Who this book is for&amp;lt;/h4&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This book is for software engineers, security researchers, and professionals working in software development and testing who want to deepen their expertise in reverse engineering and cybersecurity. Aspiring malware analysts and vulnerability researchers will also benefit greatly. Prior experience with Java or Python and a foundational understanding of programming is recommended.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;👨‍🏫 Author(s): David Álvarez Pérez, Ravikant Tiwari&lt;br&gt;📅 Released: 2025-01-17T00:00:00Z&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Contribute to Open Source Projects</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/library/view/contribute-to-open/9781098174262/</link><description>&lt;div&gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This selection of shortcuts will enable you to improve your communication, critical thinking, documentation, and networking skills. With these critical non-technical skills under your belt, you&amp;#x27;ll be well equipped to become a fully rounded developer or engineer.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;👨‍🏫 Author(s): Charles Humble&lt;br&gt;📅 Released: 2024-10-14T00:00:00Z&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Address Technical Debt and To-Dos</title><link>https://learning.oreilly.com/library/view/address-technical-debt/9781098172749/</link><description>&lt;div&gt;&amp;lt;span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This collection is designed to equip developers with practical strategies and techniques for writing high-quality, maintainable code in contemporary software development environments. Clean code significantly impacts the efficiency of software development processes, the ease of collaboration within teams, and the long-term maintainability of projects. Using these shortcuts, software engineers can enhance their coding skills, improve code readability, reduce technical debt, and ultimately deliver more robust and scalable software solutions. The collection addresses common challenges such as debugging errors, refactoring, writing tests, making peer reviews and ensuring code consistency across projects. Developers will learn valuable skills such as effective code structuring, writing meaningful variable and function names, implementing design patterns, leveraging automation tools for code formatting and testing, and adopting principles like SOLID and DRY. This collection also includes guidance on writing and reviewing AI-generated clean code.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;👨‍🏫 Author(s): Maximiliano Contieri&lt;br&gt;📅 Released: 2025-02-11T00:00:00Z&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>